<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>05. Oct 12 on HIST3000|CLCV3000</title>
    <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/5/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 05. Oct 12 on HIST3000|CLCV3000</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Original content by Shawn Graham licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#39;license&#39; href=&#39;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#39;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a rel=&#39;license&#39; href=&#39;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#39;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#39;Creative Commons License logo&#39; style=&#39;border-width:0&#39; src=&#39;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc/4.0/88x31.png&#39; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br&gt;Site logo &#39;archaeological information&#39; by corpus delicti, GR, The Noun Project.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/5/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Module 2: Considering/Critiquing</title>
        <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/5/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:09 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/5/instructions/</guid>
        <description>What Gets Counted, Counts 
Goals for this week  recognize the strengths and weaknesses of our graveyard coding scheme uncover the ways in which &amp;lsquo;counting&amp;rsquo; hides or highlights the past encounter CSVs, SQL, and R and how to do some basic statistics  Listen  Feed for the podcast here. Transcript here.
Read  ‘What gets counted, counts’. Chapter from Data Feminism by Catherine D’Ignazio and Lauren Klein link Labrador, Angela.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Basic Stats in R</title>
        <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/5/basic-r-stats/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/5/basic-r-stats/</guid>
        <description>R is a programming language for statistics that is used frequently by archaeologists (the other popular option is Python). One of the advantages of scripting or writing out your analysis as a sequence of commands is that anyone can look at your code and understand what you did and why it worked.
 Launch a virtual computer running RStudio in your browser by right-clicking on this link. nb If no one has launched this virtual computer in a while, it can take several minutes to launch; but once someone else has launched it once, it&amp;rsquo;ll be faster for the rest of us.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Databases</title>
        <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/5/databases/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/5/databases/</guid>
        <description>In the Open Digital Archaeology Textbook Environment, look at section 2.4 on databases; then start up the binder in a new tab by right-clicking this link. This is a computational notebook: a computer that you access through the website.
These notebooks are generated from a static collection of files. The generated &amp;lsquo;image&amp;rsquo; - the virtual computer - loads up quickly when someone has recently generated it, but if it&amp;rsquo;s been a while since someone tried to start up this notebook, it can take several minutes - 15 to 30 - before it finally launches.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>KoBoToolbox</title>
        <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/5/kobotoolbox/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/5/kobotoolbox/</guid>
        <description>Introduction   The KoBoToolbox is an open source platform that allows you to design quite complex data collection forms, for use via computers or devices, both online and offline.
Ipads and similar have been used in archaeology since their invention, at places for example like Pompeii and other sites destroyed by Vesuvius. The potential applications for devices like this to speed up data acquisition and analysis practically fill entire volumes, but at the same time, leave some archaeologists worried that we&amp;rsquo;re missing something fundamental about doing archaeology, that we need a &amp;lsquo;slow&amp;rsquo; archaeology to counter them.</description>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>