<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>03. Sept 27 on HIST3000|CLCV3000</title>
    <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 03. Sept 27 on HIST3000|CLCV3000</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Original content by Shawn Graham licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#39;license&#39; href=&#39;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#39;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a rel=&#39;license&#39; href=&#39;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#39;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#39;Creative Commons License logo&#39; style=&#39;border-width:0&#39; src=&#39;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc/4.0/88x31.png&#39; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br&gt;Site logo &#39;archaeological information&#39; by corpus delicti, GR, The Noun Project.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
      
      <item>
        <title>M1 Wk3: Instructions</title>
        <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/3/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:42 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/3/instructions/</guid>
        <description>Field work and ethical data collection II Goals for this week  Continue the Graveyard Project Create some 3d models of grave stones Develop a webmap of the site Explore the connections between what you are doing and what you are reading: graveyards are emotional spaces  Listen  Feed for the podcast here. Transcript here.
Read  Cook, Katherine. 2018 Negotiating Memory: Funerary Commemoration as Social Change in Barbados. African and Black Diaspora: An International Journal.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Photogrammetry</title>
        <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/3/photogrammetry/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/3/photogrammetry/</guid>
        <description>Introduction Photogrammetry is the process whereby multiple photographs of an object are stitched together to make a 3d model of the object; the photographs are then draped over the model to make it photorealistic. Because of the physics of photography (focal distances of lenses and so on) a computer can calculate the relative positioning of overlapping points it identifies in multiple photographs, and with a bit of trig it works out the points-in-space.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Webmaps</title>
        <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/3/webmaps/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/3/webmaps/</guid>
        <description>Introduction In this tutorial, I re-purpose some instructions from my Crafting Digital History class on how to build a web map using open source code from Leaflet. The idea here is that you learn to build a map and get it online: and then you modify it to display
 the cemetery that you have worked on the location of stones  The East End Cemetery website maps a historic African American burial ground in Henrico County and the city of Richmond, Virginia, and uses Leaflet:</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Spatial Archaeology</title>
        <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/3/spatial-archae/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/3/spatial-archae/</guid>
        <description>Introduction This page is for those of you who zipped through the other materials this week.
Remember: just because I give you all these options does not mean you must complete all of them. I&amp;rsquo;m asking you to start with the easier ones, and then push yourself to try the others. Spatial archaeology looks at the patterning of the remains of human activity in (usually geographic) space over time. It can encompass working with geographic information systems, and it can encompass web mapping (on which see ODATE 3.</description>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>