<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CLCV3000|HIST3000A: An Introduction to Digital Archaeology</title>
    <link>https://shawngraham.github.io/digiarch/</link>
    <description>Recent content on CLCV3000|HIST3000A: An Introduction to Digital Archaeology</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under CC BY-SA 4.0 {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 11:30:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://shawngraham.github.io/digiarch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Week 3</title>
      <link>https://shawngraham.github.io/digiarch/schedule/wk3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 11:30:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shawngraham.github.io/digiarch/schedule/wk3/</guid>
      <description>Week 3</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessment</title>
      <link>https://shawngraham.github.io/digiarch/syllabus/assessment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 11:30:05 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shawngraham.github.io/digiarch/syllabus/assessment/</guid>
      <description>Nota bene: There is no midterm. There is no final exam. Each week, there are tasks for you to attempt. Sometimes there is a choice of which tasks to do; in those cases, I&amp;rsquo;m not looking for the number of these that you complete, but that you push yourself out of your comfort level. What&amp;rsquo;s more, it&amp;rsquo;s OK if something doesn&amp;rsquo;t work &amp;lsquo;perfectly.&amp;rsquo; The reflection on the process, both your fails and your successes, is the important thing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Outcomes</title>
      <link>https://shawngraham.github.io/digiarch/syllabus/syllabus-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 11:30:04 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shawngraham.github.io/digiarch/syllabus/syllabus-3/</guid>
      <description>Questions I developed this course with a couple of questions in mind, things I wanted to know the answers to. Digital archaeology - what the hell is it, anyway? What is it for? Is it just a &amp;lsquo;follower&amp;rsquo;, repurposing other tools &amp;amp; techniques, a supporting skill for &amp;lsquo;real&amp;rsquo; archaeology? Let&amp;rsquo;s set ourselves a grand challenges: what can digital archaeology be?&#xA;This course is a formalized exploration of these questions; I do not know the answers!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>General Philosophy</title>
      <link>https://shawngraham.github.io/digiarch/syllabus/syllabus-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 11:30:04 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shawngraham.github.io/digiarch/syllabus/syllabus-2/</guid>
      <description>The Most Important Idea Archaeology isn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily about the past. It&amp;rsquo;s about the materiality of the past and present and in many ways, the future. We try to understand what it is to be human through the extended abilities that tool use, that objects and their agencies, give to us. The digital tools we use are entangled with and extend humanity in powerful ways - and in 2025, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to see how digital technologies have extended humanity&amp;rsquo;s worst impulses.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 1: Jupyterlite</title>
      <link>https://shawngraham.github.io/digiarch/materials/wk1-jupyterlite/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shawngraham.github.io/digiarch/materials/wk1-jupyterlite/</guid>
      <description>👋🏻 Hi!&#xA;Let&amp;rsquo;s do some coding. The interface below accepts python code. Try copying and pasting this:&#xA;text = &amp;#34;Oh yeah, digital archaeology!&amp;#34; print(text) into the gray box at the bottom of the interface below. Then, hit shift+enter while your cursor is in the box:&#xA;Now try this:&#xA;one = 1 two = 2 print(one + two) See how easy that was? You just entered some python code into a coding environment powered by a version of the Python language.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 1: Hypothesis</title>
      <link>https://shawngraham.github.io/digiarch/materials/wk1-hypothesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shawngraham.github.io/digiarch/materials/wk1-hypothesis/</guid>
      <description>While watching this video, turn on the closed captions.&#xA;Create an account at hypothes.is:&#xA;Get the Chrome app or the Firefox bookmarklet:&#xA;Make sure you&amp;rsquo;re logged in:&#xA;Then join our HIST3000|CLCV3000 reading group. If you happen to be reading something, and see an existing annotation that interests you, hit the &amp;lsquo;reply&amp;rsquo; button on the annotation to start a conversation! Sometimes, the person to whom you&amp;rsquo;re replying might be a previous year&amp;rsquo;s student, but that&amp;rsquo;s ok; they might enter into conversation with you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 1: Github</title>
      <link>https://shawngraham.github.io/digiarch/materials/wk1-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shawngraham.github.io/digiarch/materials/wk1-github/</guid>
      <description>If any of the instructions below are unclear, annotate this page with hypothesis while being logged into our course reading group. If you spot someone asking for help and you can offer advice, respond to the annotation.&#xA;The sequence of steps below might be a bit different by the time you read this; Github often mucks about with its look and feel. Examine the steps first, and if what you encounter is a bit different than this, you should be able to work out the basic actions to take from this walk-through.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 1</title>
      <link>https://shawngraham.github.io/digiarch/schedule/wk1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 11:30:04 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shawngraham.github.io/digiarch/schedule/wk1/</guid>
      <description>Each week, I will lay out goals for things I want you to pay attention to, I will give you something to listen to, and I will give you things to read, and things to do.&#xA;Our overarching goal this week is to set up your digital archaeology workflow. This involves creating a place to lodge your materials (a data repository via Github), a place to make notes and explore code (we&amp;rsquo;re going to use a thing called JupyterLite), and a way of being social with your community of nascent digital archaeologists (a social annotation layer for the web called Hypothes.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
