<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>02. Sept 20 on HIST3000|CLCV3000</title>
    <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 02. Sept 20 on HIST3000|CLCV3000</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Original content by Shawn Graham licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#39;license&#39; href=&#39;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#39;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a rel=&#39;license&#39; href=&#39;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#39;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#39;Creative Commons License logo&#39; style=&#39;border-width:0&#39; src=&#39;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc/4.0/88x31.png&#39; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br&gt;Site logo &#39;archaeological information&#39; by corpus delicti, GR, The Noun Project.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
      
      <item>
        <title>M1 Wk2: Instructions</title>
        <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/2/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:48 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/2/instructions/</guid>
        <description>Field work and ethical data collection Goals for this week  Find a local historic graveyard (current graveyard is OK) Begin recording some gravestones Create a rough map of the site  Listen  Feed for the podcast here. Transcript here.
Read  Cook, Katherine. 2018 Open Data as Public Archaeology: The Monumental Archive Project. AP: Online Journal of Public Archaeology 3: 177-194. link Lacy, Robyn S. 2018. Public Engagement through Burial Landscapes: Cupids and Ferryland, Newfoundland.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Graveyard Project Rationale</title>
        <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/2/rationale/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/2/rationale/</guid>
        <description>Annotate this page with hypothesis while being logged into our course reading group with connections to other things you&amp;rsquo;ve read or thought about during your studies. If you spot an interesting annotation by someone else and it strikes a chord, respond generously to the annotation. Introduction I wanted you to have some experience of collecting data, and of how data models (or our expectations of what we&amp;rsquo;ll find) influence the subsequent work that we can do with the information that we collect.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Graveyard Project Alternative</title>
        <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/2/alternative-project/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/2/alternative-project/</guid>
        <description>Annotate this page with hypothesis (while being logged into our course reading group) with connections to other things you&amp;rsquo;ve read or thought about during your studies. If you spot an interesting annotation by someone else and it strikes a chord, respond generously to the annotation. It may be that it is not feasible for you to go out into your community and visit a local graveyard for the purposes of this course.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Working Safely</title>
        <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/2/safework/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/2/safework/</guid>
        <description>If any of the instructions below are unclear, annotate this page with hypothesis while being logged into our course reading group. If you spot someone asking for help and you can offer advice, respond to the annotation. Introduction This week, I am asking you to go out into your community and find a historic graveyard to work on. There was a graveyard in the middle of a field not far from the childhood home of a friend of mine.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Making a Sketch Map of Your Site</title>
        <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/2/sketchmap/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/2/sketchmap/</guid>
        <description>Before you head out to the graveyard that you intend to record, I want you to make a sketchmap to bring with you.
While the digital recording system that we are using can read the geolocation of your device when you are standing at a stone, the accuracy of that location might not be enough for us to understand any spatial patterns that might exist. While testing the system in a local graveyard, I found that stones a few feet apart would show up on the map (using my cellphone&amp;rsquo;s geolocation) hundreds of feet apart.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Record</title>
        <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/2/do-the-project/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/2/do-the-project/</guid>
        <description>If any of the instructions below are unclear, annotate this page with hypothesis while being logged into our course reading group. If you spot someone asking for help and you can offer advice, respond to the annotation. You will need   a smartphone, tablet, or laptop
  measuring tape (metric)
  compass (optional)
  notebook
  if you don&amp;rsquo;t have a device that you can take into the field, you can print out multiple copies of the data entry form behind this link and then enter the data using the forms below on a desktop computer later.</description>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>