<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>10. Nov 22 on HIST3000|CLCV3000</title>
    <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/10/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 10. Nov 22 on HIST3000|CLCV3000</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Original content by Shawn Graham licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#39;license&#39; href=&#39;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#39;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a rel=&#39;license&#39; href=&#39;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#39;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#39;Creative Commons License logo&#39; style=&#39;border-width:0&#39; src=&#39;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc/4.0/88x31.png&#39; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br&gt;Site logo &#39;archaeological information&#39; by corpus delicti, GR, The Noun Project.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/10/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
      
      <item>
        <title>M3 Wk10: Instructions</title>
        <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/10/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/10/instructions/</guid>
        <description>Communities Goals for this week  Participate in some crowd-sourced &amp;lsquo;citizen science&amp;rsquo; archaeology Build your own research compendium for work you&amp;rsquo;ve done on the graveyards project Build a simple website aimed at explaining your research compendium to an interested public.  Listen  Feed for the podcast here.
(For more about the Alexandria Archive Institute, go here)
Read  Morgan, Colleen, Robert Carter, Michal Michalski. 2016. The Origins of Doha Project: Online Digital Heritage Remediation and Public Outreach in a Vanishing Pearling Town in the Arabian Gulf.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Sharing Authority</title>
        <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/10/sharing-authority/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/10/sharing-authority/</guid>
        <description>Archaeologists have used digital media in a variety of ways to try to reach new audiences. I want you to explore the following sites and annotate what you find, using our hypothes.is reading group (nb don&amp;rsquo;t use the &amp;lsquo;public&amp;rsquo; group!), tying what you&amp;rsquo;re seeing to ideas you encountered in the readings.
 https://www.dayofarchaeology.com/ (worldwide) and Ben Marwick&amp;rsquo;s Analysis of the posts Archaeology in the Community (US) http://www.archaeologyincommunity.com/ DigVentures (UK) https://digventures.com/  Then, I want you to actually sign up and complete some of the possible &amp;lsquo;citizen science&amp;rsquo; tasks at Micropasts (UK) https://crowdsourced.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Research Compendium of One&#39;s Own</title>
        <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/10/start-compendium/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/10/start-compendium/</guid>
        <description>This exercise depends on a complicated series of dependencies that do not play nice with the online RStudio binder I set up for you. Try installing R and RStudio on your own machine if you want to give this a try. Otherwise, I would suggest giving this a pass. You could try rstudio cloud which you can sign up for a free account with using your github credentials; or try to install the free RStudio desktop (which also means installing R first).</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Static Websites</title>
        <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/10/static-websites/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:09 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/10/static-websites/</guid>
        <description>Building a website from scratch can be onerous. Using a system like Wordpress or Squarespace etc can leave you locked in to someone else&amp;rsquo;s platform (and any security issues that might entail).
Here, we&amp;rsquo;re going to build a simple website that uses nothing but text files as its source; these text files will always be readable into the future, and you can also copy them to your own machine so that they&amp;rsquo;re always handy, ready to be transformed into something else.</description>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>