<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>09. Nov 15 on HIST3000|CLCV3000</title>
    <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/9/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 09. Nov 15 on HIST3000|CLCV3000</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Original content by Shawn Graham licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#39;license&#39; href=&#39;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#39;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a rel=&#39;license&#39; href=&#39;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#39;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#39;Creative Commons License logo&#39; style=&#39;border-width:0&#39; src=&#39;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc/4.0/88x31.png&#39; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br&gt;Site logo &#39;archaeological information&#39; by corpus delicti, GR, The Noun Project.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/9/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Module 3: Communicating</title>
        <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/9/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/9/instructions/</guid>
        <description>Communicating Digital Archaeology As we start the final portion of this course, please take a moment to skip to week 12 and note Options A and B for the completion of Consolidation III and the Exit Ticket.
Goals for this week  explore how archaeologists communicate digital archaeology professionally reuse archaeological data from a research compendium  Listen  Feed for the podcast here.
Read  ‘The Numbers Don’t Speak for Themselves’ Draft chapter from Data Feminism by Catherine D’Ignazio and Lauren Klein link Ben Marwick, Carl Boettiger &amp;amp; Lincoln Mullen.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Archaeology Data Service</title>
        <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/9/ads/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/9/ads/</guid>
        <description>Introduction In this exercise, we&amp;rsquo;re working with data deposited in ADS. The code at the bottom is an adaptation of Rachel Optiz&amp;rsquo;s notebook, &amp;lsquo;Exploring published data from the ADS&amp;rsquo;. Dr. Opitz&amp;rsquo;s work is written in Python, if you want to take a look at how she does it.
Any data published as CSV files with the ADS can be pulled into R for exploration, asking your own questions with it, and generally doing research.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Archaeologists Teaching Archaeologists</title>
        <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/9/archaes-teaching-archaes/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/9/archaes-teaching-archaes/</guid>
        <description>Introduction The same workflows that enable us to replicate someone&amp;rsquo;s analysis and research can also be used to teach digital archaeology. At the Society for American Archaeology conference in 2017, Matt Harris and Ben Marwick created a repository to teach archaeologists some of the basic archaeological uses of R. We&amp;rsquo;re going to re-run that workshop here.
Get set up Launch the binder containing R Studio. This will open up the Jupyter file explorer for our binder.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Replication as Teaching</title>
        <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/9/replication/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/9/replication/</guid>
        <description>Introduction Ben Marwick et al have made the argument that an extremely effective way of teaching archaeology data science is to have students try to replicate the findings of archaeologists from the published journal articles. (You can read the preprint here).
Of course, this depends on archaeologists publishing both the code and the underlying data for their work, something that is unfortunately still comparatively rare. When the results of archaeological research can&amp;rsquo;t be replicated or examined, there is an argument to be made that the research is unethical.</description>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>