<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Transcripts on HIST3000|CLCV3000</title>
    <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/transcripts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Transcripts on HIST3000|CLCV3000</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Original content by Shawn Graham licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#39;license&#39; href=&#39;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#39;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a rel=&#39;license&#39; href=&#39;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#39;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#39;Creative Commons License logo&#39; style=&#39;border-width:0&#39; src=&#39;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc/4.0/88x31.png&#39; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br&gt;Site logo &#39;archaeological information&#39; by corpus delicti, GR, The Noun Project.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:08:29 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://digiarch.netlify.app/transcripts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Module 1 Episode 1</title>
        <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/transcripts/episode-1/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://digiarch.netlify.app/transcripts/episode-1/</guid>
        <description>Transcript of this week&amp;rsquo;s podcast episode.
Part I Hi everyone!
Welcome to introduction to digital history.
I don’t know about you, but I can’t stomach any more zoom meetings. There’s something horrible about having to stare off-centre at your camera so that it appears like you’re looking out of your little window box at everyone else; but everyone else is staring off camera too, and frankly the whole thing feels like horrible small talk at an awkward faculty social event.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Module 1 Episode 2</title>
        <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/transcripts/episode-2/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://digiarch.netlify.app/transcripts/episode-2/</guid>
        <description>Transcript of this week&amp;rsquo;s podcast episode.
Part I This week you&amp;rsquo;re going out into the field. But which field? When I was a kid, there was a graveyard on the other side of the dirt road from our farm. It had about six or seven headstones, and an old wrought-iron fence that surrounded the little plot. One stone was flat on the ground, at the centre of the graveyard. Almost like a lid.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Module 1 Episode 3</title>
        <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/transcripts/episode-3/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://digiarch.netlify.app/transcripts/episode-3/</guid>
        <description>Transcript of this week&amp;rsquo;s podcast episode.
Part I Last week, I went to a graveyard not too far from my house. It took me about 15 minutes to walk there, crossing roads with heavy traffic. It&amp;rsquo;s in the corner of a city park, underneath some trees. The ground outside the little graveyard&amp;rsquo;s precinct is lumpy and uneven, and, as I peer into the underbrush, I&amp;rsquo;m pretty certain that I&amp;rsquo;m seeing the foundation pit of a small structure.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Module 2 Episode 1</title>
        <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/transcripts/m2-episode-1/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://digiarch.netlify.app/transcripts/m2-episode-1/</guid>
        <description>Transcript of this week&amp;rsquo;s podcast episode.
Part I My job was to copy the information in the paper recording sheets into the Access Database. Each box on the form had a count for a different type of pottery. Each paper form had a digital analog on my screen. I got pretty fast at running my finger down the paper form, and banging in numbers on the keypad. But every so often, there&amp;rsquo;d be a horrible warning noise: computer says no.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Module 2 Episode 2</title>
        <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/transcripts/m2-episode-2/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://digiarch.netlify.app/transcripts/m2-episode-2/</guid>
        <description>Transcript of this week&amp;rsquo;s podcast episode.
Storytime Welcome to week 6, the halfway point of the course, and the last week before the fall reading week and Hallowe&amp;rsquo;en. I want to tell you about the library at the British School at Rome. Imagine a room two stories tall, lined with bookshelves. There&amp;rsquo;s a walkway around where the second floor would be; you can go up a spiral steel staircase and browse those shelves up there, looking down on the scholars at their desks below.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Module 2 Episode 3</title>
        <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/transcripts/m2-episode-3/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://digiarch.netlify.app/transcripts/m2-episode-3/</guid>
        <description>Transcript of this week&amp;rsquo;s podcast episode.
Part One I wrote a book called &amp;lsquo;Practical Necromancy&amp;rsquo;. Or rather, I wanted to call it &amp;lsquo;Practical Necromancy&amp;rsquo; but various folks felt that would be a bit off-putting. So instead, it ended up being called &amp;lsquo;An Enchantment of Digital Archaeology: Raising the Dead through Agent Based Models, Archaeogaming, and Artificial Intelligence&amp;rsquo;. It came out this past summer. The key idea in it, which I learned from the work and writing of Sara Perry, is the idea of &amp;lsquo;enchantment&amp;rsquo; as a mode of being open to the world.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Module 3 Episode 1</title>
        <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/transcripts/m3-episode-1/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://digiarch.netlify.app/transcripts/m3-episode-1/</guid>
        <description>Transcript of this week&amp;rsquo;s podcast episode.
Part One I love Phineas and Ferb, and I empathize so much with Dr. Doofenschmirtz. Look at him, out there every day, building new devices and clearly communicating what they do, how they do it, his plans and everything. He might not be an effective evil villain, but he&amp;rsquo;s a very good communicator.
We&amp;rsquo;re now in the final third of this course, which I&amp;rsquo;ve called &amp;lsquo;Communicating&amp;rsquo;.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Module 3 Episode 2</title>
        <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/transcripts/m3-episode-2/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://digiarch.netlify.app/transcripts/m3-episode-2/</guid>
        <description>Transcript of this week&amp;rsquo;s podcast episode.
Part One A number of years ago, I found some contract work with a small online liberal arts college in the United States. When I say small, I mean: there were 3 of us. So we each got to wear different hats on a rapidly shifting basis. Sometimes I taught, sometimes I tried to fix the learning management system. Sometimes I was writing code to sort out our online registration system.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Module 3 Episode 3</title>
        <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/transcripts/m3-episode-3/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://digiarch.netlify.app/transcripts/m3-episode-3/</guid>
        <description>Transcript of this week&amp;rsquo;s episode.
Part One This is it, gang. The end! You&amp;rsquo;ve made it through. Take a moment, and look back at everything you&amp;rsquo;ve done this term. Look at your glorious failures. Look at your spectacular successes. Each one of you has at least one of both! You&amp;rsquo;ve come a long way, as the advertisement used to have it.
We&amp;rsquo;re ending the term by looking at digital creativity, computational creativity, gaming, and augmented reality.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The One with the Exit Ticket</title>
        <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/transcripts/exit-ticket-episode/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://digiarch.netlify.app/transcripts/exit-ticket-episode/</guid>
        <description>Transcript of this week&amp;rsquo;s episode.
Part One </description>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>