<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>11. Nov 29 on HIST3000|CLCV3000</title>
    <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/11/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 11. Nov 29 on HIST3000|CLCV3000</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Original content by Shawn Graham licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#39;license&#39; href=&#39;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#39;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a rel=&#39;license&#39; href=&#39;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#39;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#39;Creative Commons License logo&#39; style=&#39;border-width:0&#39; src=&#39;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc/4.0/88x31.png&#39; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br&gt;Site logo &#39;archaeological information&#39; by corpus delicti, GR, The Noun Project.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/11/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
      
      <item>
        <title>M3 Wk11: Instructions</title>
        <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/11/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/11/instructions/</guid>
        <description>Creativity &amp;amp; Digital Storytelling Goals for this week  Last week was about getting your work out there. This week is about finding the compelling story, the enchanting story, the heart-centered work of archaeology.  Listen  Feed for the podcast here.
Read  Perry, Sara. 2019. The Enchantment of the Archaeological Record. European Journal of Archaeology. 22.3, 354-371 link González-Tennant, Edward. 2010. Virtual Archaeology and Digital Storytelling: A Report from Rosewood, Florida.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Digital Creativity</title>
        <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/11/creativity/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/11/creativity/</guid>
        <description>Introduction There are lots of different ways to engage with archaeological data in creative ways that can create an affecting and effective story. Epoiesen - A Journal for Creative Engagement in History and Archaeology has published a number of pieces that use a wide variety of modes to tell the story, from photo essays to time lapse art to papercraft.
For this exercise, I want you to scratch that creative itch.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Archaeogaming</title>
        <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/11/archaeogaming/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/11/archaeogaming/</guid>
        <description>Introduction Humans have made virtual worlds since time immemorial (see, for instance, Lascaux). Hadrian&amp;rsquo;s Villa at Tivoli was a virtual world. Disney World is a virtual world. Online is a virtual world but it&amp;rsquo;s still the real world.
As this map put together by Andrew Reinhard and I suggests, there are a lot of dimensions to archaeogaming. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if it&amp;rsquo;s still on Netflix, but the &amp;lsquo;Atari: Game Over&amp;rsquo; documentary is worth a look because it is a case of quite literal archaeology of video games.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Augmented Reality</title>
        <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/11/augmented-reality/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://digiarch.netlify.app/week/11/augmented-reality/</guid>
        <description>Introduction I read a lot of science fiction when I was a kid. Augmented and virtual realities were always a part of the scene, in the stuff I read. I&amp;rsquo;ve spent a lot of time over the past ten years or so trying to bring those visions to life, given the level of my tech chops and the available technologies I had to play with, with various degrees of success. I shelled out for an Oculus Rift SDK v2, put it on, plumbed it into Minecraft, and promptly had to lie down for three hours because my head went one way and my body went the other.</description>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>