<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Syllabus on HIST3000|CLCV3000</title>
    <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/docs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Syllabus on HIST3000|CLCV3000</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Original content by Shawn Graham licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#39;license&#39; href=&#39;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#39;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a rel=&#39;license&#39; href=&#39;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#39;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#39;Creative Commons License logo&#39; style=&#39;border-width:0&#39; src=&#39;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc/4.0/88x31.png&#39; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br&gt;Site logo &#39;archaeological information&#39; by corpus delicti, GR, The Noun Project.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 14:09:21 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://digiarch.netlify.app/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
      
      <item>
        <title>1. Course Description</title>
        <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/docs/1-coursedescription/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:39:09 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://digiarch.netlify.app/docs/1-coursedescription/</guid>
        <description>HIST3000|CLCV3000 Fall 2021 Department of History, Carleton University Once the excavation is over, what happens to the information created through archaeological research? How do archaeologists use digital technologies on site, in the lab, or on the web? This course explores the intersection of digital technologies and computing with archaeology. We will explore the ways theory gets embedded into computation; perhaps there is even a theory of digital archaeology? We will explore how digital technologies allow us to ask questions that would otherwise be impossible to ask.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>2. Learning Outcomes</title>
        <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/docs/2-learning-outcomes/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:38:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://digiarch.netlify.app/docs/2-learning-outcomes/</guid>
        <description>Questions I developed this course with a couple of questions in mind, things I wanted to know the answers to. Digital archaeology - what the hell is it, anyway? What is it for? Is it just a &amp;lsquo;follower&amp;rsquo;, repurposing other tools &amp;amp; techniques, a supporting skill for &amp;lsquo;real&amp;rsquo; archaeology? Let&amp;rsquo;s set ourselves a grand challenges: what can digital archaeology be?
This course is a formalized exploration of these questions; I do not know the answers!</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3. Course Calendar</title>
        <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/docs/3-schedule/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:38:48 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://digiarch.netlify.app/docs/3-schedule/</guid>
        <description>Each week involves completing to the best of your ability various exercises; you will document your progress in a weekly log that you will keep online. Log entries are required to be completed by the Sunday evening at the end of the relevant work. A final reflection piece is due at the end of the course. See the assessment page for further details.
Some exercises are collaborative for the class as a whole.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4. Assessment</title>
        <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/docs/4-assessment/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:38:59 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://digiarch.netlify.app/docs/4-assessment/</guid>
        <description>There is no midterm. There is no final exam. Weekly Work Each week, there are tasks for you to attempt. Sometimes there is a choice of which tasks to do; in those cases, I&amp;rsquo;m not looking for the number of these that you complete, but that you push yourself out of your comfort level. What&amp;rsquo;s more, it&amp;rsquo;s OK if something doesn&amp;rsquo;t work &amp;lsquo;perfectly.&amp;rsquo; The reflection on the process, both your fails and your successes, is the important thing.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5. Common Regulations</title>
        <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/docs/5-commonregs/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:39:06 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://digiarch.netlify.app/docs/5-commonregs/</guid>
        <description>The following are the University regulations common to all History courses, that I am obligated to share with you. COPIES OF WRITTEN WORK SUBMITTED Always retain for yourself a copy of all essays, term papers, written assignments or take-home tests submitted in your courses.
PLAGIARISM The University Senate defines plagiarism as “presenting, whether intentionally or not, the ideas, expression of ideas or work of others as one’s own.” This can include:</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>6. Contacting Dr. Graham</title>
        <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/docs/6-contact/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:39:06 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://digiarch.netlify.app/docs/6-contact/</guid>
        <description>Dr. Graham can be found online at
shawn dot graham at carleton dot ca
or on Twitter at @electricarchae.
He will be present in our class discord server every day.
If we ever get out of quarantine, and you&amp;rsquo;re in Ottawa, he often haunts the Library coffeeshop.
Online Office Hours Dr. Graham will be present in our Discord server every Wednesday from 1 until 3, and quite possibly the evenings too.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>7. Colophon</title>
        <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/docs/7-colophon/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:39:06 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://digiarch.netlify.app/docs/7-colophon/</guid>
        <description>As a general philosophy of learning, I do not aim for coverage. Rather, I am trying to help you learn the skills that you will need to uncover whatever aspect of method and thought that will help you with your research goals. A big part of that is trying to teach how to deal with what might feel like &amp;lsquo;failure&amp;rsquo;, on first blush. I want you to swing for the bleachers, and not to be afraid of whiffing on the ball.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>8. Reuse</title>
        <link>https://digiarch.netlify.app/docs/8-reuse/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:39:06 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://digiarch.netlify.app/docs/8-reuse/</guid>
        <description>Original content by Shawn Graham, is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.
Please feel free to reuse exercises in your own course materials, with a link back to the original page.
Corrections, modifications, additions are welcome; please fork, and then modify accordingly. Once you&amp;rsquo;re ready, make a pull request. The original repository is at [https://github.com/shawngraham/hist3908](https://github.com/shawngraham/hist3908.
All contributions will be duly credited.</description>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>